Um,
humanity is still here. So,
most weeks when I do this, uh, there's
actually a lot to talk about in the
market. Uh, when when you get a week
like this where
you get all the bare porn out on Sunday,
I get contacted by more hedge fund
people in a weekend in a long time to
see how the AI trade is going to play.
Uh, and pretty much everyone who reached
out where I said this is just another
one of these knee-jerk one day and then
by the time we get a week to 10 days
later, nobody will remember it. I think
everyone keeps learning their lessons on
this. Uh, but overall it was a very
quiet week for stocks. It was a very
quiet week for uh AI trades. It was just
overall a very quiet week despite the
fact that we had
AI pause, 10% chance humanity dies, oil
soaring higher on Monday, 10 year rates
get to 2007
levels for the first time. Fed raises in
a hawkish hike and if you sold the
market on Monday morning when it opened,
you lost. if you sold it uh at the close
on Wednesday, which a lot of people uh
that I follow said this was the time to
be out of equities and everything else
and yet somehow another we made we were
able to rally. The story of the week and
the story for the month is crypto. I
have talked endlessly about this and we
are finally at the point. So last May to
June I said that by the time we get to
se September October we will be at the
most important inflection point for
crypto and the reason would be because
of the merging of AI agents. AI and
crypto are together. Crypto does not
exist without AI. It was built for AI
and most people don't recognize that. So
before I start this I want to make sure
there's a lot of things I'm going to go
through here. This week I will be
sending out my first video on uh on
crypto for subscribers. So for those of
you who watch this every week that have
been waiting for it, this will be
basically a very extended version on why
now. Uh I'm not going to go through all
of that today. I'm not going to take you
through the details. Um but as I've
said, I've created an index. It made new
highs for the year today. I posted that
in X for macro people. This is the most
important macro trade of everyone's
existence. This is the beginning of
something that is very very similar to
the times that I traveled to China. For
any of you that I traveled to China with
who I've not spoken with, those times
that we went to China from 2003
to 2013 when they were building roads
bigger than what they needed and they
had ghost cities and all of this stuff,
the.com bubble where we were building
the infrastructure necessary, but we
didn't actually get
the iPhone until 2007. So all these
stories that you're hearing about debt,
about crashes, about that, it's all BS.
It's all meant to scare you. Everything
I read on AI is just a complete
gobbledegoop of garbage. Uh it's just
people literally writing things that
have nothing to do with facts. They
might be right down the road, but you
can't argue with it if you don't use it.
And so everyone that's taking some kind
of history and pasting it over. What I
am going to do today for a bit of this
is paste over where we are in crypto,
why it was built, why we've gone through
this long period of 16 years, which is
very similar from the internet to when
the iPhone came out. It's almost the
exact amount of time and why the iPhone
and the app store was why this works
because there is no Uber, there is no
Airbnb, there is no almost everything
you do in your life without the
smartphone and without the app store.
And for crypto, I will tell you guys,
your entire world is changing. There has
not been a macro change like this in the
history of mankind. We are going to a
digital transaction with digital agents,
digital employees, everything is going
digital. And so if you want to
understand what tokenization is, if you
want to understand the names that are in
there, what Zcash is, what Bit Tenzor
is, what a go up and down the line, all
of these things are going to be a part
of your life whether you like it or not.
So you either learn or you don't. And at
least with me, you're getting someone
who's doing it from a systems thinking
perspective, who's a macro person for
those who know me and they like what I
do on the AI side. They like the way I
talk about macro. I'm been spending my
time to make sure that I can give you
the same thing in crypto in that way.
All right, you guys can read this on
your own. Do not take anything I say as
being certain. I'm wrong all the time.
The key is maximize upside, minimize
downside.
I'm going to show this again because
after today, quarter to date,
here are the stocks. So, I'm going to
say this right now.
I don't think we will ever have another
big bull market in stocks like the one
we saw in the first quarter of this
year, the first two quarters of this
year for AI. I believe the multiple
compression is the old system basically
going through something there. So the
Fed's going to have they've chosen to
raise rates. The only way I thought we'd
get a surge in stocks would be if they
cut rates. The fact that they raised
rates and stocks are just sitting here
while earnings continue to grow. You'll
still get returns in stocks, but
remember bonds are basically unchanged
for how long now? I mean, I'm sure we'll
be here in two years and we'll say it'll
be a decade, but regardless, stocks so
far this quarter, S&P up 2%. NASDAQ down
three,
semis down 14,
Ethereum up 66%, Bitcoin up 53%.
Salana up 38. Those are the three main
ones. Those are the layer ones that I
want you to focus on. But underneath the
hood for crypto to get a quick thing out
while you're sitting there spinning your
wheels for not not just this month, for
the entire quarter trying to chase
stocks up and down, responding to oil,
responding to rates, and watching this
whole thing and just getting gutted.
Everyone made their money in the first
two quarters of the year when we got the
rally in AI. I'm not sure going forward
that we're going to have the kinds of
rally that are necessary for people to
go because I do think the market will go
higher. If you're running long short, I
would guess between now and the end of
the first quarter, we're going to see a
good rally in stocks. But I wouldn't bet
heavy on it because I don't think you're
going to get much return. But in crypto,
here's what you're getting on Friday.
I'm not showing you the names. These are
the names in my 46 name portfolio. Some
of these are public stocks. This is the
vertical they represent.
21% in a day, almost a hundred for the
month. Look at these numbers. Is it
above the 50-day? Yes. Yes. Yes. We're
at a different point now. Here's what
the chart looks like. I said my 46 name
index broke to new highs for the year.
That puts Bitcoin up significantly from
here. Another 15% from here. Uh and this
is Bitcoin overlaid with it. The
correlation remains basically one for
one. The difference is the ecosystem is
doing better. Bitcoin, remember, is part
of the ecosystem. So, I posted this in
X. 10% chance AI kills humanity. 100%
chance crypto was built for AI. So, for
all you guys who've made money on AI
this year, all the macro teams that have
jumped into AI, all the pod teams,
crypto is now where you want to have
your focus. Why now? I'm not going to
spend time on today, but for those I did
travel to China. China built ghost
cities. Ghost cities, there's no
economic activity, but there's a bunch
of infrastructure. That's where crypto
is. The problem is crypto was never
meant for human beings. Even though the
crypto gang thought it was, it was never
going to get the wealthiest people that
own the $900 trillion, the banks, the
institutions to actually start using it.
What is going to use it? what cares
about it
are AI agents and they're already
starting to and so this is the reason
why I have waited and I've been patient
and this is why why now is about the
perfect convergence liquidity plus AI
plus the blockchain everything that
you've learned about macroeconomics in
terms of well the liqu and and in crypto
I hear this from both sides the
liquidity cycle we're doing M2 does not
matter anymore M2 relative to what's
happening with tokenization relative to
what's going to happen with the velocity
of money. We are going to see an
explosion in the velocity as everything
moves on chain gradually by time because
it will be cheaper to deal on uh on
chain. Will people be slow to move? Of
course, that's what they did with Uber.
We all know parents and grandparents
that either never used Uber or they
barely moved over. But in a world where
every penny matters, where time matters,
you're going to use the agents and
they're here and they're getting valued
high. This is private companies, too.
So, I'm going to take you through that
as we go on. The reason now is because
we couldn't have crypto benefit until we
reached the automated AI researcher.
This is hedge fund manager Leopold Ashen
Brener from his situational awareness
paper, the 165page paper he wrote in
2024.
When we hit this point, we get an
explosion in all of these things,
including GDP, military edge, robots,
science and technology, cognitive labor.
I'll go through this.
This is where we are. Okay, we're at
that inflection point, which is why
crypto matters. And this is the last
thing I'm going to do on crypto before I
go through the week that was I want you
to understand in someone who has spent
now the better part of five years mainly
situated on Bitcoin but then spreading
out into the ecosystem in particular
over the course of the last two
thinking that you understand crypto or
that you don't need to know it is the
same thing for me as trying to say to
people if you know baseball you don't
know cricket. And I'm bringing this up
because the the complexity of learning a
completely new language. Why
tokenization matters, why stable coins
matter, what is Ethereum, what is
Salana, what is Bitcoin, what is Zcash,
why how do they all fit into the
equation. It takes a lot of time. And so
for the people making decisions at the
highest level of a hedge fund, it's very
very hard to pick this up. And so what I
will be spending my time doing for the
next two months for sure as I go through
why now then I will start going through
each of the 10 verticals probably two or
three a week to take you through the
names to give you an understanding of
what's going on. That is what will be on
the subscriber website for hedge funds.
If you don't pay for the subscriber
website or mutual funds or whatever
you're going to need to this stuff is
going behind the payw wall. This is the
stuff that I will be talking about. This
is what I do presentations on right now
for financial advisors and RAAS. If
you're worried that you are going to
fall behind with your clients, the same
way with AI, this is far more important
than AI because it's very easy for
someone to understand what Micron does.
They just have to go read. But to
understand what Zcash is and what near
is and I can go on and on. It's going to
take a lot more learning and your
viewpoint of it is that it's a scam. So
the week that was I did my thing on
Friday last week Daario came out and
said we have to slow down. That got
everyone freaked out. So Monday we get
in here. You get cyber gapping up which
moves the software sector up. You get
semi semiconductors down. So what you
end up with is a 10% the biggest
outperformance of software verse semis.
I'm sure it hurt a lot of people.
Anthropic researcher believes more than
10% chance AI could kill all humans.
Incredibly stupid. Um, and no reason for
you guys to to think about it, warn if
if that's what's going to happen. It's
not something you can go defend against.
Um, and it's very hard to come up with
how you kill all of humanity. So, we can
kill people and I'm sure we will. Um,
Anthropic Co warns AI agents swarms
could seize the internet within a year.
This is a story now going around more
and more. Again, I 100% believe that
this is possible, especially as you read
the hugging face thing. 100%. I
subscribe to the fact that will there be
an issue? Yes. And will humans be
scared? Yes. Just like they've been with
every new technology, bar none. This is
not the first time we've worried about
humanity. Could AI really wipe out
humanity? It's a global thing. So, let's
go through the bearish forecast that we
get constantly and the reality. So, the
reason I said the BS and the bear porn
and whatever you're reading, whether
it's Michael Bur, Jim Chenos, whether
it's the stuff in X that comes out all
the time, GPU prices are going to fall.
I get stuff every single week, guys. I
had a CPA send me something this week to
try and prove to me that here's just the
fact it may happen. We may get to a
point where the frontier model companies
are selling their incredibly important
brains to nobody. the open source are
not as good. None of that stuff is the
same as what they're doing. Who's
solving the math prizes? It's anthropic
and open AI. Now, again, this may change
over time, but they have a huge
advantage, and it's very clear at this
point that they've hit some kind of
recursive self-improvement by the fact
that we're getting models out quicker
and quicker, and now they've reached a
point where they're scared because
they're ahead of the safety side. So, if
you read through all of these things
that have been out there and then you
read at the facts, we need things to
change. So, if you're listening to
people and getting worried, it's costing
you money. Now, right now, the market's
not moving, but as we get through
earnings and we have the next wave of
this, at some point here, we're going to
go higher. The mag seven, if you have
not seen, are near all-time highs.
That's an important read to me with
consumer agents. I'll get into that as I
go through this. Demand is greater than
supply.
It's going to remain that way for a long
time in my opinion. I don't see how we
can catch up. It's just physics. We'll
solve problems with intelligent uh with
Einstein level intelligent but we still
you can come up with a solution and say
this is a better battery but then you
have to go build the bit the better
battery. It's not that simple to get the
parts. This guy gets 172 million views.
Obviously this is involving politics.
Obviously this is involving geopolitics.
There is no way for this thing to go
this viral and for this to be there.
We're ahead of a midterm. So, if you
guys are going to listen and get all
caught up in this, it's obvious that
this is part some of this because it is
a major issue. Whether this slows down
the uh anthropic open AI because they
have to redo the risk side, I don't
really know. But I do know this. It just
seems way too political at this point
and way too we don't want to be
responsible for the liability of what
may happen. Again, Jeffrey Hinton, the
godfather of AI, has been talking about
how dangerous AI is for a long time. We
had 87 million views on this Matt
Schumer one that there'd be no jobs by
2028. The Satranei one by 2028, same
thing. 28.7 million.
Oh, we have a cancer vaccine, 11
million. People want to see the end of
the world. That's what sells and that's
what gets the hype. And I said
geopolitical. If the Russians, Chinese,
Iranians, and anyone that's at battle
with the US wants to break us
politically, the easiest thing to do is
continue to make data centers an issue,
make AI an issue, and everything else.
Whatever the the facts are, we had a
cancer vaccine. I can't think of
anything more important. And yet, we're
focused on things which are the same
things that have gone on. This had three
million views. This was June 6, 2023.
This was less than six months after the
launch of ChatGpt. Why AI will save the
world. He had to write this because
people are freaking out. So, this has
been going on, guys, for a long time.
China's not buying Silicon Valley's call
for an AI slowdown. They would love an
AI slowdown. We also had oil prices go
up. Scary. As I've talked about,
oil is $105, guys. The next time someone
tells you oil is going higher and they
show you a chart, you tell them Jordy
Visser was in China in 2008. Oil was
$150
can household net worth is up, I don't
know, three times where it is. We've
added a hundred and something trillion
dollars. Gas as a percentage of
disposable income for this country has
never been lower. We are now a gas
provider. Yes, some of the world is
going to have problems in in gas being
higher, but at the same point, their net
worth is higher as well. This is just
completely stupid. Does it mean headline
inflation will be a little bit higher?
Yeah, but it's not 2022.
Stocks falls, Fed delivers hawkish rate
hike. We just raised 25 basis points.
Maybe we'll do another 50 over the
course there. I didn't think we'd do one
this year because CPI core CPI has kept
going lower, but they decided to do it
because for whatever reason he was put
into it. I have no idea. I really don't
care. They're panicked about rates,
whatever. But here's the facts. This is
not 2022. We don't have 10% inflation
playing from a behind the curve. We have
core CPI going down. As I'm going to
show you with Goldman Sachs forecast and
with everyone that knows, the PCE core
is going to go down because of things
that are coming out of it. The main
point of this is they raised 25 basis
points. this as much as I want people to
think as I saw a bunch of macro people
getting paid money to deliver forecasts
saying that this meant stocks would go
down because stocks don't like when
rates go higher. I'm going to say this
once I'm going to show you guys as
things go on before 2008
before then we had recessions
or before 2009 and the reason we did is
because rates really mattered. When
rates went higher, the economy was based
on corporate debt at companies that ran
into really big problems and homeowners
whose house prices went down because
rates went higher. Right now, we have
tons of equity in the housing market and
everyone's trapped because they locked
in mortgages at lower rates. So, we
don't have the rate sensitivity there.
Second thing is, I don't know if you
guys know this, Nvidia's $5 trillion. As
I'll show you later, the total sum of
the consumer discretionary household
durables, retails, restaurants, those
companies, including some big ones like
Home Depot and McDonald's, not including
Amazon,
one a half trillion. Nvidia is five and
a quarter trillion. The stock market
represents what is driving growth. The
Mag 7 are much bigger. They have no rate
sensitivity. whatsoever. The AI trade,
despite what you'll hear from bond
people, have no rate sensitivity
whatsoever in what's going on. Mark
Xandandy,
these are true. Economy is already
growing near full potential. True.
Operating at full employment. True.
Inflation is too high to be sure,
running above 3%, but much of that is
the fallout from high energy prices and
tariffs. True. AI related infra
investment appears to be powering the
economy. True. While the nonAI economy
is already struggling, true. To hit its
inflation objective, the Fed either
needs to rein in the AI boom, true, or
put even more pressure on the rest of
the economy. Neither is a good outcome.
This is the point I keep making. Your
job is to make money. It is not to sit
there and think about the past. Remember
Visser Labs, the V the left side linear.
This is where your economists are giving
you BS.
The Goldman P [clears throat] core
inflation forecast. [cough]
again the effects of temporary factors
the portfolio management effect all
these things everyone knows this I just
don't understand why people don't talk
about it in terms of what's going to
happen PCE core is the only one so core
CPI is down at 2.3 plus%
it's barely above PC core is higher for
the reasons that they have here the
software and accessories is due to this
having a different waiting in the micron
thing there's a double counting side
there's everyone already knows this, but
we're scaring people. So, is the market
responding? Is the bare market
happening? Yes, it is. Here's the
restaurants trading at 52- week lows.
Look at this collapse on rates and oil.
XRT. Now, this includes Amazon, but it's
equal weight. So, it's a small portion
of Amazon. Here we go. Falling
continuously.
Here's the household durables. This
includes homebuilders. Includes Home
Depot. Look at it trading off. This is
the Goldman Sachs lowinccome consumer
basket getting near, it's the lows of
the year, near 52- week lows. Like I
said before, here are the GIX level two
EPS revisions.
Look at these massive numbers. The AI
trade and comm and energy massive
numbers.
Here's what you guys are looking at.
This is the ones where the revisions are
going lower which is all related to the
consumer. Now media and entertainment
you have to strip out Google, Netflix
and Meta and then what you're left with
on the revisions negative I that's the
11 trillion. So when you go through this
the total sum of these is very very tiny
and that's why you have this. So in 2022
when it was time to be bearish stocks as
people are telling you now and writing
saying they're raising rates you have to
be bearish stocks you don't have to be
bearish stocks here is revisions massive
negative in 2022 and again people were
forecasting a recession never happened
but equities did run into trouble the
hangover from 2021 and the overhiring
the overspending that's what ended up
raining in this time it's not happening
now could we get a you know GPU prices,
chip prices to come down. Could we see
bottlenecks that slow things down and
then you're just left with the debt
sitting out there? Of course, we don't
have any indication of that like I've
said and at this point right now because
AI is accelerating, I'll take the other
side on this. Um here's 2025. And the
reason I wanted to bring this up again,
I'll show this later too, but these
periods in time were during periods of
this is the tariff fears and then this
is the 2022. These were recession fears.
We don't have that right now. So, I put
this out from a bearish week. You had a
hot PPI the Thursday before. You had a
hot CPI the Friday before. You had 10%
chance humanity dies. You had a pause in
AI. You had the Fed hawkish hike. Brent
hits 110 for the first time uh or hits
110. I don't know if it was the first
time from since whatever March. Tenure
rates at the highest level since 2007.
That was the week. And for the week, the
S&P futures finished down about 30 basis
points.
But the AI bare reading hits 53.
So I wanted to give you guys
Well, I guess I'll get into that later.
Here were the daily moves. This is in
sigas. So for all of the negative stuff
that's been happening with oil with
Iran, we can't even get a one sigma move
on depressed V. So, this is taking the
implied V, which is the VIX, converting
it into a daily move, and then taking
the daily move. We're just not, we've
been basically going sideways. This is a
nice looking reverse and head and
shoulders chart. But regardless of that,
this is only a five-day chart. This is
when people were calling me. And by the
way, for people calling me asking me
where futures are going to open up on on
Sunday night, you guys start looking at
spy per. Just go into Coinbase and start
looking. You got to get used to 247
tokenized trading, guys. It's time. Um,
you got to start getting some get
getting getting getting ahead of the
program here. Um, so we open down here
and we're here. So you get this gap.
Well, that cost you money for a while.
Then the Fed came out. Oh, hawkish hike.
Let's sell it off. And then the next day
we go right back up right through it
immediately. Kind of come down a little
and then we continue going on. So since
June 25th, that's what those circles
were that I wanted to highlight to you
guys. Since June 25th,
oil prices have gone from 67 to 92. So
that's 25 bucks. Since June 25th, since
June 25th, 10ear rates have gone from
430 to 502. You guys are worried now. I
mean, look how far we've gone up.
Two-year rates have gone from 415 to
473.
Oh my gosh. Since June, since right
there, tech momentum fell 48%.
Oh wow. We've seen credit spreads widen,
CDS has widened on the hyperscalers.
And here's the Mag 7. This was the Mag 7
on June 25th.
So if you're worried about the AI trade,
isn't it going to have to come to some
degree from these guys? It's not going
to be from Anthropic and OpenAI stock
price. when we see their earnings, it
could come through. Now, during true
bare markets where there's bare things,
the mag seven goes down. So, this is
during the uh selloff here. You need the
mag 7 going down, not about to make new
all-time highs. Same thing down here.
So, I just bring this up again so you
guys can start to go through. If you're
worried about the bond market, like I've
said repeatedly for a while, you should
have credit spreads widening and you
should have bond volatility spiking
higher. We can't even barely get a move
in bond. Here is HYG relative to EF, my
proxy for the S&P N4 credit to strip out
yield differential. And we made new
highs
for the last year in HYG relative to EF.
And remember when this sold off here,
what was this off of? Well, this was on
the private credit side. So, it was
responding to that. This was on
combination. You had Iran, you had all
this, but private credit started this
move here. Right now, private credit HYG
is going higher. S&P that's where it was
on June 25th. So, despite all the rise
in tenure rates and all the ride in
crude. So, I just want to tell you
something. If it was able to do this
with crude moving up that much, we're
now to the end of the year. There is a
less than 40% expectation of any kind of
ceasefire with Iran. Now that we have a
hawkish height and we already have rates
at 5%. Isn't the risk for everyone who
said sell equities this week if crude
falls 10 bucks at some point for any
reason which a tweet could do. Do you
think stocks won't be at new all-time
highs if they can handle all the bad
news? AI trade again. This is when I did
my famous bailout of Micron and then
this is when I did my June 4th was when
I did my the midcycle slowdown. I am
still not increasing AI and I've had a
lot of people reach out. I about 20% of
my portfolio right now is in the AI
trade. Back here it was about 80. As I
mentioned, crypto and silver now make up
most with the crypto massive performance
since I did the rotation.
It's much bigger. And I keep adding to
crypto. I'm not adding to the AI names
at this point. I still have Marll. I
still have Nvidia as the two biggest.
Eli Liy, which I consider an AI name, is
a big position, but that's not the AI
trade that you guys are looking for. I
still own Yes. A AOI. I still own
Fluence even though it's fallen about
80%. For those of you who are trading,
if you're picking oneoff names in here,
the reason I have a bunch of names is
because I move my portfolio around based
on the things that I provide the biggest
opportunity. Even though crypto's had a
big rally, if you ask me what has the
best riskreward for me over the next
year, it is still crypto, not the AI
infrastructure trade. And that is
because crypto is an AI trade. It is
part of my thematic AI portfolio, but it
is not part of the agent one which I'm
working on now. Again, this is about as
bullish as it gets. The MAG7's up there.
They benefit tremendously from the AI
agents. Here is the AI 53 level. This is
a big level except for this point.
point. I mean, this goes back only two
times that we've hit this level in the
last four years were during the complete
chaos of 2022
and during the tariffs
to show you how unusual it is. AI be a
AI AI bearish over since 1990. So, 1875
weeks only happens four and a half times
out of 100. Okay, these are the
performance going forward for these when
you combine this with a VIX which is
lower than 20. So think about that. You
have a bearishness
but the cost of insurance is low. Well,
that seems like a good time to be
looking at the long side and it is n 89%
of the time. It's 10 times over the last
whatever years doesn't happen often. 53
basis 50.53%.
Now to also get it above 50 in a
structural bull market defined by the
S&P above its 50week moving average that
happens 1% of the time again very good
positive numbers with all three
conditions so VIX is low we're in a
structural bull market bearishness is
high only nine times and again very
solid numbers so
this doesn't happen and as I wrote
this would be one of the more structural
positive things to be in a bare market
while people are getting bare bearish to
be in a bull market while people are
getting bearish and that's where we are
now. So for everyone saying sell
equities I think you're in a very
dangerous position based on history
given that you're joining the bear crowd
which is already there climbing the wall
of worry. This is a classic definition
of it
and again the mag seven here they were
back on that June 25th when all the bad
news and they're near the highs of a
quarter. Now,
the Mag 7, the reason I brought them up
there is there's another thing going on.
The Mag 7, very seldom this year, have
all seven of them, all seven of them.
So, that includes the hyperscalers, plus
Apple, plus Nvidia, plus Tesla.
They're uh they haven't been above the
50-day moving average, all of them,
except for eight days the entire year.
These are the periods. The last time was
June 4th. So I do view this as if we're
going to get a big move higher in
equities, I think one of the reasons
would be because all of the mag seven
are benefiting. Now if you add in
Oracle, you get less days. The reason I
care about Oracle is because it is a
very large stock and a hyperscaler. And
I believe this bearish sentiment, a lot
of it for the market began in October of
last year with the CDS blowing out on
Oracle. And I don't think it's ever left
people. I think the people that thought
it was a bubble in October missed the
entire rally in terms of semiconductors
and now they're sitting there still
bearish because the AI trade has peaked
and even though it's still up massively,
Korea is still up 60% year to date. Uh
Taiwan is about to make new all-time
highs, all of that, you've had eight
days. Now to put that in context, this
year only four and a half% of the
trading days has that occurred in 2023.
36% of the time we've been declining on
the MAG 7 being above the 50-day. I
think this is an important period to
watch because they're breaking out and
unlike the prior times where Meta was
collapsing and Microsoft was collapsing
and the AI was going to destroy. They're
all sitting there and I think that's
because of AI agents, they all benefit
from AI agents. All of them. And that's
the point I want to get into. The reason
the economy is different again the
economy is based on the top 10%.
the bottom part of the economy gets
transfer payments. So unless you're
going to fire people, which is not
happening, how do you get anything bad
in the stock market if everyone has
money to spend and you're doing it
because oil is going higher, which I'm
telling you does not matter the way it
used to. Gas prices as a percentage of
disposable income remain near historic
low. If you do gas prices as a
percentage of household wealth, it's an
even bigger joke. Oil doesn't matter the
way it used to. The AI boom is
transforming America. We know that this
is chat GPT. This is what's going on. I
mean, give me a break. Jensen Yuang
spoke this week. So for everyone who
listened to the anthropic kid, who
listened to Dario Moda, just go listen
to Jensen. And at the all-in summit,
whenever you listen to him, especially
at a time like this, and yes, President
Trump called him while he was on stage,
but this is really about what he said
about everything happening today and the
industrial revolution that's going on.
Don't lose focus on this because you're
worried about people telling you it's
time to be bearish. Brad Gersonner went
through everything and I thought he was
very, very balanced in terms of the way
that he approached this. It's worth
listening. It's worth going through. So
the AI labs just in terms of this
anthropic and open AI. This is kind of
the you know really the the critical
thing and he talks about it. So I'm not
giving you any of the uh I'm not taking
you through the transcript uh in terms
of the important points because I think
you guys should just go watch those two
and get this thing out of your mind.
Okay? If you haven't brought this up,
bring it up in an LLM and start doing so
you can check some of the things I'm
going to show you. But this is really
important. Whatever you think or know of
Liupold uh Ashen Brener, this paper came
out 2024, the decade ahead,
two almost I mean he's six the the the
models are six months ahead. So this
automated I AI researcher point is
really really critical. So this is
effectively one of the um slides. I
believe it's on page 71. But this is
what happens. And the reason this is
important, don't think of it as AGI or
ASI or anything like that. I'm going to
take you through, but this is the point
where what's happening right now is
exactly what this is, the hackings.
So that's the negative side of reaching
this point is the hugging face episode,
the mythos fears. We've reached this
point, but there's a lot of good that
comes from it too. So we've already
accomplished based on his research and
these are the facts between the releases
and the key things that have happened
this year. It's really important for you
to understand how fast this is moving
and ignore the people that are telling
you that there's too much debt. I don't
know how to get this out of people's
mind. It is so insane to me that people
are worried about the investment grade
debt for the best balance sheets on the
planet when they're sitting there
watching that the United States of
America can have $40 trillion of debt,
which everyone keeps telling you and Ray
Dalia has tried to make a living post
the hedge fund telling you how bad this
is going to be because we have so much
debt. Yes, Japan's been in this problem
forever. AI is a government thing.
There's no way we allow the whole thing
to come down. So, this comes down to
usage. And like I said before, I don't
know how to tell people. We're past
humans adopting it. That's why this is
working. And that's why what he's saying
is so important. When you get to the
point of the RSI, the recursive
self-improvement, the point where you've
got autonomous researchers, that means
companies can just say, as I showed with
Astra last week, build this for me. and
it's built. We're at the point now where
that means that Salesforce.com can hand
out products to people with agents. Like
the agentic side is where adoption
starts to accelerate and it goes at the
expense of expenses. It's a productivity
boom. And that's what he talks about in
the paper. That's where we are right now
is millions of AI researchers operating
faster than humans. But it is all this
point here that was supposed to be in
2027 that's happening now early stages
now. This is the part here and that
means we're accelerating things and
nobody expected it to happen this fast.
So that's why an anthropic researcher
believes they're absolutely 10%. In
fact, Elon Musk gave an interview with
Ted Cruz during the summer where he said
there's a 20 maybe 10% chance advanced
AI leads to human extinction within the
next 10 5 10 years. That would be the
headline for the media. But then he
says, but there's an 80 to 90% full that
it's extreme prosperity.
So if you're managing money and you
worry about this if there's no humanity,
don't worry. Nobody's going to pay you.
So there's no need to bet on it. The
expected value of a 10% chance of the
end of humanity and 90% chance of
abundance is basically all upside. So
you can sit there and play the game. You
can listen to it. You can pretend that
that's there. I'm just telling you the
demand side is from nonhumans. The
adoption is happening from agents. This
is why it's so important to crypto. As
someone who set up a Robin Hood
blockchain uh wallet, it took me four
hours. I use AI all day long. There were
so many things to get through. So, I
need an agent to do this for me quickly
and go through the pain to speak the
language and not have to go look it up.
That's why we're entering a period where
the models are coming out so fast that
you don't know how to keep up. Which
model do I get? Astra came out. Fable
5.1. That's because the models are
coming too fast. That's an indication
that the agentic world is here and
humans can't handle the speed. We cannot
handle the speed. But luckily, the debt
is in human speed. The it the demand is
going to come from companies that have
trillions of dollars of revenues that
will easily be able to give trillions of
dollars to the model companies. And
there's no way that open-source is as
good as the model companies. So, it'll
be 90%. If you want to use Jensen
Yuang's thing, there's plenty of water
that we use in our lives. Not a lot that
we pay for, but we all pay for bottled
water. So, again, you can go through
this thing and try to figure it out
where it is the positive side of agents
forms. And this is where I come in to
hopefully the same way I have the
Agentic infrastructure portfolio, which
I'm saying will continue to outperform
the S&P 500 by 20 to 40% a year. So,
there's alpha. All of those hundred
names, in my opinion, will outperform.
They'll go at different times. Not all
of them will work. My job is to give you
an index that works. If you try to pick
one name, you're taking now risk in that
one name. The agent swarms. How do you
get long? Here are all the things that
come with that. We're at the time for
robotics and physical systems, which
means Tesla should be doing well. Okay,
that's one to watch. the consumer
agents. Well, this is where Microsoft,
Salesforce.com, Meta, Apple, all of them
fit into the consumer agent side. Uh,
when you get into the digital labor
side, when you get into this, this is my
favorite one, the scientific discovery,
which I'll kind of go through, but agent
swarms solve unfinished IP. There's a
business there. Autonomous commerce,
this is your crypto side. So, again, all
of this stuff is necessary. The
infrastructure is still there. I will
create an index which will have all of
these and all the names that I think
benefit in there that'll go on the
subscriber wall sometime over the course
of the next two weeks but I am focused
on crypto mainly. So when you think
about it this way and you go through it
agents are opening up all of this part
here. So we had the compute and power
that led us to get the intelligence up
to an IQ at Einstein level and now
cryptos are the main benefit and because
there is no investment there at all
because it is completely not understood.
Unlike the power and compute side which
got got way too big way too quick,
this one's going to take years. So go
spend your time now on it. Go understand
the things I'm talking about. Longevity.
This is a phenomenal place to make
money. And it fits with the unfinished
IP endorant knowledge. Any IP, any
biotech company based on Navier Stokes
is worth a lot of money. The data
proprietary data all of a sudden. So
fact set Thompson Reuters because we
have agents now. All of the data becomes
more valuable. The cyber become cyber
becomes more valuable. Everything
becomes more valuable. That's why you've
seen this and embodied AI starts to take
off because they need the agentic side
too. So again, you can go through this
on your own. We've reached this point.
It's connecting his vision at when we
reach here. This is the infrastructure
side. This only happens when we have
enough compute. So I want you to think
this way as I go through this, which is
two ways to organize intelligence. You
just saw Oppenheimer. This is the
easiest way to understand the importance
of this. In the movie, Groves wanted to
compartmentalize
the different verticals and have them
come in and bring their information with
one little thing side. He wanted to
coordinate scientific collaboration.
When you go read the Navier Stokes side,
this is what the agents did.
Humans could have solved Navier Stokes
in my opinion if they had all worked
together. But the Field Medal, the Nobel
Prize, the way academia is set up,
you've heard me all speak negatively
about my experience and my belief in
what the school system does. It is the
best way to get people to be trained for
a particular major. But that ended with
the internet. And with the internet,
we've gotten to a point where you have
to be creative. And it's only gotten
more and more. So Steve Jobs, all of
these people that invented and were the
wealthiest people, go back and look at
their job, their work situation. It's
not all of them because then you started
getting into the engineers, but again,
having creativity, thinking outside the
box, using the other side of your brain.
Well, agents are basically going to be
solving things and they're going to be
doing it just like Oppenheimer. So there
were about 600 brainiacs uh at the
Manhattan project. There were a lot more
people in general. But of the brainiac
side, the Einstein side, Navier Stokes
was solved by 10,000 agents working for
88 hours.
All problems will be solved. And that's
why I've compared this to that. And this
is why the acceleration of disruption
will increase. AI native businesses have
a huge advantage. The democratization of
intelligence is best used in
organizations where they don't have the
friction and the difficulty of meetings
and people and decision makers and
devil's advocates and all of this stuff
that goes on and I've been a part of
that and I work there. So traditional
human research here you go all the
friction that gets to an answer. the
agent swarms why they can do something
that Einstein or a problem that was
there before Einstein
and for everyone saying oh yeah the guys
who were working on it said that they
must have stolen their stolen or why
aren't they just happy that it was
solved and they were part of the process
if that's what happened. So again,
humans are already saying this is bad
for science. This is bad for math. This
will again, nobody's going to be happy
in this with humans. That is the lite
story. That is every anger that comes
with technology. So I've been spending
time I am writing something on the
revaluation of IP in an agentic world
and how the value of it goes higher.
This fits in with my Eli Liy theme. Eli
Liy has tons of capital coming in. They
are buying IP every day. They are also
bringing in biotech companies into toune
lab which you guys should go look up and
then understand the value of toune lab
from the collaboration in the swarm
perspective. So I believe that biotech
is part of the consumer agent trade that
Eli Liy is part of the consumer agent
trade and the way a biotech will trade
is like it did with Maderna. as we get
breakthroughs, they don't trade in a
fundamental basis. They just gap higher.
And you don't need all of them to go
higher to win. If you get a 10 bagger
and a 20 bagger and a 30 bagger and I
fully expect that we will see that in
the biotech side over time. Muse was
released. We are getting the first
personal AI agent built for everyone.
Now, the reason this is important is I
want you to go back to when Mark
Zuckerberg spoke at a town hall in June
and he said, "We are way behind on the
AI side." and it was related to AI
agents. The latest viral AI assistant
rocketing across Silicon Valley. Buzzy
startup Instinct, which is fundraising
at a 2 and a half billion valuation.
That was on August 26, 2026.
Go read about Instinct. Now, if you
don't want to read about it, there you
go. Here's a YouTube Instinct AI is for
real. This came out this week.
Here's what I'm I'm not going to go
through everything, but basically, and I
talked about this with Pomp on our video
this week because he's been using it. I
have not, but all of these horrible
things like applying for visas, and I
and yes, if you have an assistant at
work, but that assistant at work is
doing it. all the personal assistance
stuff, what they can do, the time
savings, the money savings, coordinating
with other people's agents, negotiating,
reducing bills, cancelling subscription.
All you got to do is tell this thing it
it will go out there and do it
just needs the information. So AI
agents, techbased AI assistants are a
hot market with Instinct, W Joe Town,
Ali, and Meta's Muse Agent, which
launched last week, vying for users
attention.
We're at the consumer agent side, guys.
I've been waiting for this. I didn't
expect it to happen this fast, but when
we get the hugging face incident, when
we get the Navier Stokes incident, that
means we're there. When we get the pause
AI incident, that means we're there. We
are at the agentic side. And so, you're
going to have a new economy. And for
everyone on the macro side where it was
well M2 growth then we get nominal GDP
that translates into some multiple and
topline revenue. We get earnings to grow
and we hire people. The missing link
we're not hiring anyone zero people. The
only people getting hired are in
healthcare. Earnings are booming at
close to 30%. Margins are exploding but
we've broken this chain and this chain
is going to get further broken because
we don't need the liquidity anymore. The
liquidity is going to come from
tokenization.
And if you don't understand that yet,
that's why you're going to watch the
videos,
okay? To see the productivity breaking
out. US earnings are breaking out of a
90-year channel. Now, this does this
this is not talking specifically about
any kind of profitability related to
productivity.
On the upside, it's incredible when you
consider the high growth periods of the
past that it's just broken out. software
revenue per employee from Warren Pies
this week again
channel from 2000 to 2023 you don't even
get like a mega spike from the 2027 in
the iPhone now all of a sudden the
second we get AI
and that's the exact timeline that he
has you get a dramatic shift software
revenue per employee
all right let's finish up with crypto
clarity didn't go through. Another bad
news item for the week for crypto. So
you had all the other bad news, oil
prices higher, rates going higher, no
debasement trade, everything is at for
the last time. I will say this to both
crypto people and macro.
The time where crypto matters is when
rates don't matter because all
innovations eventually hit a spot where
they grow regardless of rates. That is
the whole point of innovation. But when
you're a new innovation and you're not
being used and it's all speculation, you
should be correlated to liquidity. We
are at the breaking point. So for all
the crypto crowd that's looking for
liquidity, that's not what this is
about. The liquidity is going to come
from the tokenization of dormant assets.
It's going to come from the AI agents
using and driving revenues, driving uh
fees, driving activity, and the
developers going and building there. So,
the Clarity Act doesn't get through, but
US markets are set to expand to a
23-hour weekday trading on December 6th,
huh? So, that's just weekday.
Eventually, we'll be doing weekends. Per
can get you there. Now, US Securities
Regular rolls out a five-year exemption
for tokenized stocks.
Guys, this is this is why this is so
important. So, here we go. If you build
it,
they will come. The infrastructure comes
first. The economy begins when the
people arrive.
Humans could never use crypto. But the
ghost city, the old famous Chinese ghost
city. What have we been building,
waiting for this to light up and be
economically there right now? It's a
complete ghost city. It is like exactly
like
2007 and 2008. What was 20207 and 2008?
That was the post.com bubble. we still
had nothing going on. Now in 2007 it did
change. Then we got the uh the great
financial crisis. So let's say 2004 2005
the infrastructure was built. The
telecom companies blew up. That's what
happened in crypto in 2022 and all of
those entrepreneurs and the stuff that
went on. There's been dumping of stuff.
You've had that companies bailing out.
Everything has been an issue. But we
built the infrastructure for this. It's
all for AI agents. So when do you want
to invest? You want to invest when the
ghost city starts to fill up. When the
ghost city fills up, particularly when
there's no investment there, this will
all be new stuff and it will be taking
away from the traditional finance world.
So three trillion market cap, let's say
four after today for crypto,
$900 trillion in the fiat system. No
reason for wealthy people to invest over
here without it being fundamentals. No
need speculation wise. They got plenty
of places to speculate. The agents are
there. The agents are going to be doing
all of the business and it will generate
the flows and it's already starting to
happen. So you get crypto before and
then you get crypto after. This is where
we are in the bridge that's being built
is through tokenization and through all
the pieces. AI agents will need their
own financial infrastructure. 100%
correct. So again, here's my index. It
broke out to the highs of the year.
There are 46 names. four uh six of them
are public stocks like Coinbase, like
Robin Hood, like Circle.
The rest of them are tokens, most of
which for the majority of you, if you're
not cryptoreated, have heard of. Here's
Bitcoin. I will say it again for all the
Bitcoin maxis.
This needs to happen to move this into
the next level. You do not get to a
gold-like market cap without the
ecosystem and the usage and the
fundamental value. So, remember, Bitcoin
is macro. The fundamental bottoms up
stuff is what's driving things and what
should happen. So for all the macro
people out there, think about how you've
got bottoms up and you've got macro. A
lot of macro people I knew moved into
bottoms up eventually or bought into
businesses that way. They work hand
inand because they're important and
that's where we are. The verticals so
far this month, the digital monetary
assets which include Ethereum and
Bitcoin up 27%. But there's one name in
here that's driving most of it. The
exchange brokerage. The main thing I'm
not going to read them all. You can read
the verticals. They're all up monthto
date. Now,
again, I showed you this. Look at it on
your own.
Today, the index was up 8.4%. Month to
date up 14. Year to date, up 32. Now,
now 43 of the 46 are above the 50-day.
The 50 days rising with 37 out of 46 and
27 of the 46 are at the 200 day. This is
a beginning bull market, guys. Beginning
disclosures. I'm not here to lose you
guys money. I'm not here to make you
guys. I'm here to educate you and I'm
here to help you. So, this is the
beginning. There will be a crypto video
out this week. Uh, it'll go out sometime
during the week. I'll probably do a more
thorough market update thing, too, just
in terms of the AI thematic trade for
the subscribers. And there will be the
paper on ghost rails which hopefully
will go out either over the weekend or
on Monday, whatever the case. Uh it's
here, guys. I've talked about it for a
while. The crypto side is there. I look
forward to teaching all of you and doing
a lot of crypto events. And for those of
you who are going to be down in DC,
reminder, I will be at Freedom Tech.
Reach out to Mark Whaling. That's m
Whaling at22vresearch.com
for information and to subscribe. And
you can always go to visser-labs.com
and get your information there. Have a
good week, guys.